Guide to the Washington, DC Statehood Constitutional Convention records, 1982 MS2094
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Washington, DC Statehood Constitutional Convention records
1982
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2094
13.5 Linear Feet
Collection consists of a transcript of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitution Convention ranging in date from February 9, 1982 to May 29, 1982.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
On November 4, 1980, sixty percent of the District of Columbia (DC) residents voted and approved the District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention of of 1979, which became DC Law 3-171. This law called for the creation of a state constitutional convention, which was an initiative towards statehood. During 1981, a DC Statehood Commission was established. On November 4, 1981, forty-five delegates were elected to a Constitutional Convention to serve two or three year terms.
The elected delegates for the District of Columbia Constitutional Convention convened to write a constitution for the future state of New Columbia on January 31, 1982. On May 27, 1982 New Columbia is officially chosen as the name for the new state and the new constitution is adopted on May 29, 1982 ending the convention. On November 2, 1982, DC voters ratified the constitution for the State of New Columbia.
In 1983, a bill was introduced in Congress for the admission of the State of New Columbia into the United States, but it did not pass. This means that Congress continues its exclusive legislative power over the District.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection is a transcript of the District of Columbia Statehood Constitution Convention. They transcript covers the date range from February 9, 1982 to May 29, 1982.
Collection note
A more detailed paper index available in reading room, please see staff member for assistance.
Statehood (American politics) -- Washington (D.C.); Washington (D.C.). Statehood Constitutional Convention (1982); Washington (D.C.); New Columbia
- Transcript: 01/09/1982 (1) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 01/09/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 01/11/1982 (1) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 01/11/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 01/13/1982 (1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 01/13/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 01/13/1982 (3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 01/16/1982 (1) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 01/16/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 01/18/1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 01/18/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 01/20/1982 (1) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Transcript: 01/20/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Transcript: 01/27/1982 (1) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Transcript: 01/27/1982 (2) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Transcript: 03/06/1982 (1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 03/06/1982 (2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 03/13/1982 (1) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 03/13/1982 (2) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 03/20/1982 (1) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 03/20/1982 (2) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 03/27/1982 (1) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 03/27/1982 (2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 04/03/1982 (1) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 04/03/1982 (2) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 04/10/1982 (1) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 04/10/1982 (2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 04/12/1982 Judiciary Committee Hearing (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 04/12/1982 - Committee on Finance and Taxation Ifearing (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 04/13/1982 Committee on Business, Economic Development and Labor (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 04/13/1982-Committee on Local Government, Xntergovernmental Relations and Transition Hearing (1) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 04/13/1982 - Committee on Local Government, Intergovernmental Relations and Transition Hearing! C2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 04/13/1982 -Conmittee on Local Government, Intergovernmental Relations and Transition-Hearing (3) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 04/13/1982,-Committee on Local Government, Intergovernmental Relations and Transition Hearing (4) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 04/17/1982 (1) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 04/17/1982 (2) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 04/17/1982 (3) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Transcript: 04/24/1982 (1) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 04/24/1982 (2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 04/26/1982 (1) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 04/26/1982 (2) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 04/27/1982 (1) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 04/27/1982 (2) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 04/28/1982 (1) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 04/28/1982 (2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 04/28/1982 (3) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 04/29/1982 (1) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 04/29/1982 (2) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 04/30/1982 (1) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Transcript: 04/30/1982 (2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Transcript: 04/30/1982 (3) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Transcript: 05/01/1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 05/03/1982 (1) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 05/03/1982 (2) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 05/04/1982 (1) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 05/04/1982 (2) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 05/04/1982 (3) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 05/05/1982 (1) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 05/05/1982 (2) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 05/06/1982 (1) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 05/06/1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 05/07/1982 (1) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 05/07/1982 (2) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Transcripts, undated (Box 6)
- Transcript: 05/08/1982 (2) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 05/10/1982 (1) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 05/10/1982 (2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 05/11/1982 (1) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 05/11/1982 (2) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 05/12/1982 (1) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 05/12/1982 (2) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 05/12/1982 (3) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 05/13/1982 (1) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 05/13/1982 (2) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 05/13/1982 (3) (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Transcript: 05/14/1982 (1) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 05/14/1982 (2) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 05/14/1982 (3) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 05/15/1982 (1) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 05/15/1982 (2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 05/15/1982 (3) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 05/17/1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 05/17/1982 (2) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 05/17/1982 (3) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 05/18/1982 (1) (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 05/18/1982 (2) (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 05/19/1982 (1) (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Transcript: 05/19/1982 (2) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Transcript: 05/19/1982 (3) (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Transcript: 05/20/1982 (1) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 05/20/1098 (2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 05/20/1982 (3) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 05/21/1982 (1) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 05/21/1982 (2) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 05/22/1982 (1) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 05/22/1982 (2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 05/22/1982 (3) (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 05/24/1982 (1) (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 05/24/1982 (2) (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 05/24/1982 (3) (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 05/25/1982 (1) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Transcript: 05/25/1982 (2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Transcript: 05/25/1982 (3) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Transcript: 05/25/1982 (4) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Transcript: 05/26/1982 (1) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Transcript: 05/26/1982 (2) (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Transcript: 05/26/1982 (3) (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Transcript: 05/26/1982 (4) (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Transcript: 05/27/1982 (1) (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Transcript: 05/27/1982 (2) (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Transcript: 05/29/1982 (1) (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Transcript: 05/29/1982 (2) (Box 9, Folder 12)